cm.com 2019-05-02

# Legal

Who is CM? CM Groep B.V. 

Konijnenberg 30, 4825 BD Breda, the Netherlands

Chamber of Commerce 20095946

www.cm.com 

CM Groep B.V. operates the website www.cm.com. This privacy policy describes the way in which we store and use your personal information that we collect on our website. 

**What personal data do we process?**

When you use our website, we may collect the following personal information:

Personal Information 

  * When you register on our website or sign up for our web or email services, we may ask you to provide personal information. This includes your name, address, zip code, city, country, telephone number and e-mail address.

Log data 

  * We may collect information about your visit to this website through the use and placement of Cookies. This includes, among other things, the Internet protocol address (IP address), browser type, browser version, which pages you visit within the website, the duration of the visit and the page views of your computer. We use cookies for this purpose. You can read more about this in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.cm.com/nl-nl/over-cm/cookie-policy/).

**Why do we process your personal data?**

We process personal data for the following purposes:

• To contact you, or to keep you informed of information that we think may be of interest to you, after you have submitted a web form on our website;

• To keep you informed of (new) products and services, in which we try to take into account preferences based on services provided to you and/or interests based on the use of our website with your permission;

• To make calls using the chat option offered on our website;

• For obtaining an insight into the use of our website, as described in our Cookie Policy;

• To improve and evaluate our website and services;

• To comply with laws and regulations.

**Processing of personal data**

For checking and analyzing the use of our website, registering visitors who want to receive our newsletter, or want to visit an event of CM, we can use other service providers. These service providers may receive personal data. These service providers will only act for or on behalf of us in accordance with the purpose(s) for which the data was originally collected or otherwise legally processed. These service providers are hired by us and may only use your personal data after you have agreed to our Privacy Policy and/or Cookie Policy, for the agreed purpose. They may also not use your personal information for their own purposes, sell it to third parties or disclose it (unless required to do so by law, as permitted by us, or as stated in this Privacy Policy). 

The service providers engaged by CM are: 

Hotjar: Tool with which CM Internally analyses how visitors use our website. Results are used to enhance the CM websty and user experience.

Unbounce: Tool for creating landing pages for events. Visitors can register for such events via a landing page created with Unbounce.

Linkedin Insights: Website analytics tool that helps us to improve reporting on website usage and the campaigns we create. 

[Google Analytics](https://www.google.nl/intl/en/analytics/): Website analytics tool that helps us to improve reporting on the use of the website and the campaigns we create.

Furthermore, your personal data may be transferred to subsidiaries of CM Groep B.V. in accordance with the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

In addition, we may disclose your personal information to the government or the courts if required to do so by law or by a court or regulatory body ruling. In order to ensure that your visit to our website is as smooth, reliable and useful as possible for you, and to enable us to make the best possible use of our website, we also use cookies and similar technologies. Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.cm.com/nl-nl/over-cm/cookie-policy/) for more information about the types of cookies we use.

**Access to personal data**

You can request CM to view your personal data that we have collected. If the data contains incorrect information, you may request CM to correct, supplement or delete such data. You may also contact CM at any time to object to the processing of your personal data for marketing purposes. If you receive a newsletter from us by e-mail, you will be given an opportunity to unsubscribe at the bottom of each e-mail. 

**Security measures** CM attaches great importance to the security and integrity of its platform. Our IT department is active 24/7 to monitor security and amply meets the requirements for appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure a risk-appropriate level of security. All data is processed and stored in our own data centre, fully managed and controlled by CM. The data centre is located in the Netherlands. More information about security can be found on our website <https://www.cm.com/about-cm/security-compliance/>

**Changes**

CM reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy. We therefore advise you to check this page regularly to see if any changes have been made. If we make a significant change that affects the way in which CM processes your personal data, we will notify you of this by means of a notice on our website.

**Contact**

If you have any questions and/or complaints about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like access to your personal data, please send an e-mail to support@cm.nl
